# Kaloyan Penev

**Graphics Software Engineer** 

## **ABOUT ME**

A problem-solver interested in computer graphics, machine learning and real world applications of technology. Professional graphics engineering experience using both UE4 and Unity. Reliable work ethic and adaptive learner with a major appreciation for neat software design and clever optimization techniques.

## **PROJECTS**

### HAND POSE RECOGNITION

Python | YOLOv4 | Darknet

Hand pose recognition with real-time speeds on consumer-grade GPUs using input from ordinary monocular phone cameras. Built with the YOLOv4 convolutional neural network model.

### **GAME ENGINE - eudaimonia**

C++17 | C | OpenGL | GLSL

Data-oriented ECS framework created in native C++17 as backbone. 3D Physically Based Renderer made with OpenGL 3.3 as graphics system.

## **HOBBIES**

In my free time you can most often find me in a **volleyball** sports hall, on a **ski** slope, or out on my **bike**. Other highly preferred activities include looking for new music and generally making a game out of everything.

9	+44 7500 652536	
@	kdpenev@gmail.com	

## **EXPERIENCE**

**(**3)

#### **GRADUATE GRAPHICS ENGINEER**

https://penev.me

Hawk-Eye Innovations • Dec 2021 - Present
Unreal Engine 4 | C++20 | Qt | OpenGL | CMake

- Building out a Virtual Production application that is fully driven by in-house tracking data using a custom UE4 build and C++20, controlled by an in-house Qt app.
- Development and maintenance of Semi-Automated Offside technology precise skeletal representations of tracking data visualized both over a live video feed in the form of AR, and in UE4 space for maximum precision. Used for officiating at FIFA World Cup 2022.
- Constant optimization of existing UE4 and communications architecture. Profiling performance in order to provide the Art team with more computational budget.
- Agile development in a team of 4. Worked in both Scrum and Kanban systems. Familiar with agile ceremonies and cross-team dependency handling.

#### JUNIOR UNITY DEVELOPER

VISTA AR, Bournemouth Uni • Feb 2020 - Jul 2020 Unity | C# | HLSL | Shader Graph

- Development and profiling of AR apps in **Unity**
- Performance optimization for mobile devices
- Shader programming with HLSL and Shader Graph

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BSc GAMES SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

Bournemouth University • Sep 2018 – Jun 2021 First Class Honours (80.49%)

- Dissertation: Hand Pose Recognition 80.50%
- Graphics and Computational Programming 83.03%
- Game Engine Programming 79.00%